字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
这是我迄今走过的岁月
Here's my day so far:
进过监狱 失去了我的梦中情人
Went to jail, lost the girl of my dreams,
被别人打得屁滚尿流
and got my butt kicked pretty good.
不过 更糟的事还在后头
Still, things could be a lot worse.
噢 没错
Oh, that's right.
我快要掉下去摔死了
I'm falling to my death.
估计没更糟的了
Guess they can't.
你要问 怎么会成这样？
How'd it all come to this, you ask?
我的结局开始就已注定
My end starts at the beginning.
最初的开始
The very beginning.
没错 这就是我
Yes, that's me.
我童年相当正常
I had a fairly standard childhood.
我来自 你们可能会叫做 一个破碎的家庭
I came from, what you might call, a broken home.
确实很破碎
Literally broken.
我都八天大了 还跟父母住在一起
I was eight days old and still living with my parents.
多悲哀啊？
How sad is that?
显然 生活该向前了
Clearly it was time to move on.
这是你的仆人 他会照顾你的
Here is your Minion. He will take care of you.
给你宾奇奶嘴
And here is your Binky.
你命中注定成为…
You are destined for...
我没听到最后那部分 不过似乎很重要
I didn't quite hear that last part, but it sounded important.
- 命中注定成为…  - 什么？
- Destined for...  - What?
我登上行程 去寻找自己的命运
I set out to find my destiny.
结果 一个Glaupunkt信号区的孩子和我的想法如出一辙
Turns out a kid from the Glaupunkt quadrant had the exact same idea.
就是那天 我见到了假正经先生…
That was the day I met Mr. Goody Two-Shoes...
我们宏伟的较量从此开始
and our glorious rivalry was born.
这将是我的命运吗？
Could this be what I was destined for?
奢华 梦幻的生活
A dream life filled with luxury.
显然不是
Apparently not.
就连命运也有自己的喜好
Even fate picks its favorites.
没什么大不了
No big deal.
一个截然不同的命运等待着我
A much different fate awaited me.
[欢迎来到犯罪天才的大都会市监狱]
一个婴儿！好贴心啊
A baby! How thoughtful.
噢 对 对啊 我看到它 就想到了你
Oh, yes. Yes, I saw it and thought of you.
幸运地是 我找到了一个可爱的小地方来当家
Luckily I found a lovely little place to call home.
我们可以养它吗？
Can we keep it?
这个地方教会了我对…
A place that taught me the differences between right...
与错
and wrong.
而另一边 假正经先生
Mr. Goody Two-Shoes, on the other hand,
不费吹灰之力就过上了好日子
had life handed to him on a silver platter.
我们的宝贝会飞啊
Our baby can fly.
是啊 是啊 对你来说最棒了 亲爱的
Yes, yes, nothing but the best for you, darling.
翱翔之力 刀枪不入 发型超棒
The power of flight, invulnerability, and great hair.
但是我有厉害许多的地方
But I had something far, far greater.
我智慧惊人…
My amazing intellect...
还有创造破坏工具的本领超棒
and knack for building objects of mayhem.
过了几年 因为表现良好
After a few years, and with some time off for good behavior,
我得到机会进行学习 自我改善…
I was given an opportunity to better myself through learning...
还是在一个陌生的地方 叫什么校
at a strange place called Shool.
天才儿童学校 “专为天才儿童打造” 在那儿 我再次遇上了假正经先生
It was there that I once again ran into Mr. Goody Two-Shoes.
他那时已经有了一大批没大脑的粉丝
He had already amassed a gigantic army of soft-headed groupies.
他就靠着大秀演技 还有挥霍精美小礼品
He bought their affections with showmanship
来赚取他们的喜爱
and extravagant gifts of deliciousness.
所以我也要做出爆玉米花 把那些没大脑的白痴给争取过来
So I, too, will make this popp-ed corn and win over those mindless drones.
熄灯
Lights out.
就是那时 我学到了一个艰难的道理:
That's when I learned a very hard lesson:
好人获得所有的表扬和奉承
Good receives all the praise and adulation,
而坏人只能在角落面壁思过
while evil is sent to quiet-time in the corner.
所以能否融入群体 真不是我能左右的
So fitting in wasn't really an option.
当他们学习儿歌“海绵泡沫纸板书”的时候…
While they were learning the Ltsy Bitsy Spider...
我在学习如何随心所欲地让活化物体脱水 再水化
I learned how to dehydrate animate objects and rehydrate them at will.
有段时间 就好像只有我和我的仆人与世界为敌
Some days, it felt like it was just me and Minion against the world.
不管我多么努力
No matter how hard I tried,
我总是个局外人
I was always the odd man out,
被抛弃的人
the last one picked,
出乱子的人 害群之马…
the screw-up, the black sheep...
砸他！
Get him!
坏小孩
The bad boy.
怪人！
Weirdo!
这就是我的命运了？
Was this my destiny?
等下 可能就是
Wait, maybe it was.
我唯一擅长的就是做坏事
Being bad is the one thing I'm good at.
然后我恍然大悟: 如果我是个坏小孩
Then it hit me: If I was the bad boy,
那我就要做所有人中最坏的那个
then I was going to be the baddest boy of them all.
我命中注定成为超级大坏蛋
I was destined to be a super-villain,
我们注定要成为对头
and we were destined to be rivals.
既知难逃一死
The die had been cast,
那就开始好好经营我永恒 壮丽的终生事业吧
and so began an enduring, epic, lifelong career.
我爱它
And I loved it.
我们之间的战争愈演愈烈
Our battles quickly got more elaborate.
他赢了很多次
He would win some.
我很多时候也险些获胜
I would almost win others.
他取名为大都会侠 意为大都会市的保护者
He took the name Metro Man, defender of Metrocity.
我决定要取个谦虚点的名号: 超级大坏蛋…
I decided to pick something a little more humble: Megamind...
不可思议的帅气犯罪天才 精通所有的坏事
incredibly handsome criminal genius and master of all villainy.
超级大坏蛋
下班时间再看吧 开门
Read on your own time. Open up.
- 嘿！ - 嘣！
- Hey!  - Boo!
噢 早上好啊 监狱长
Oh, good morning, Warden.
超级大新闻: 我已经改过自新啦 而且…
Great news: I'm a changed man, and...
我已经准备好重新踏入社会 当个好市民了
and I'm ready to re-enter society as a solid citizen.
你是个大坏蛋 而且永远都是大坏蛋
You're a villain, and you'll always be a villain.
你永远不会改过自新 而且永远也不能离开这儿
You'll never change, and you'll never leave.
你真好玩
You're fun.
有人给你寄来个礼物
You got a present in the mail.
是小狗吗？
Is it a puppy?
大都会侠寄的 “让你算清八十五个无期徒刑的每一秒”
From Metro Man. "To count every second of your 85 life sentences."
很奇怪啊 没想到大都会侠也会沾沾自喜
That's funny. Never thought Metro Man was the gloating type.
噢 不过他品味确实不错 我就留下吧
Oh, but he does have nice taste. I think I'll keep it.
你可以告诉我现在几点了吗？
Any chance you could give me the time?
我可不想在大都会侠博物馆开幕式上迟到
I don't want to be late for the opening of the Metro Man Museum.
啊 不好 看样子你必定要错过它
Oh no. Looks like you're gonna miss it,
迟到个几千年了
by several thousand years.
噢 是吗？
Oh, am I?
大都会市市民们 大都会侠日快乐
Happy Metro Man Day, Metro City.
今天天气很好 我们在美丽的市中心
It's a beautiful day in beautiful downtown,
在此授予一位杰出人士 大都会侠以荣誉
where we're here to honor a beautiful man, Metro Man.
他的心海纳百川 包罗万象
His heart is an ocean that's inside a bigger ocean.
这么多年来 他以自己超凡的视觉注视着我们
For years he's been watching us with his super-vision,
以超凡的力量拯救着我们 以超凡的心关爱着我们
saving us with his super-strength and caring for us with his super-heart.
现在该我们给他些回报了
Now it's our turn to give something back.
来自罗珊・罗奇 在大都会侠博物馆
This is Roxanne Ritchi, reporting live
落成典礼发回的现场报道
from the dedication of the Metro Man Museum.
哇 好了 现场直播让你说这种东西
Wow. OK, the stuff they make you read on-air,
真是让人太难以置信了 简直疯了
that's un-freaking-believable. It's crazy.
是我自己写的稿子 哈尔
I wrote that piece myself, Hal.
我其实是想说
What I was trying to say was,
我很难相信在现代社会中
I can't believe that in our modern society,
他们会让这种真正的艺术出现在新闻里
they let, like, actual art get onto the news.
- 真会圆场啊 哈尔  - 我们要不…
- Nice save, Hal.  - What are we...
去喝杯咖啡什么的吧
Like, let's just get a coffee or something.
拜托 该好好去体验下大都会侠日了
Come on, it's time to get in the Metro Man Day spirit.
好吧 如果我是大都会侠
Well, if I were Metro Man,
超级大坏蛋就不能老是绑架你成功了
Megamind wouldn't be kidnapping you all the time.
- 这是其一  - 嘴真甜 哈尔
- That's the first thing.  - That's sweet, Hal.
我一定会好好看着你 就像澳洲野狗看护小孩子一样
And I'd be watching you, like a dingo watches a human baby.
好吧 听起来…
OK, that sounded...
- 好吧 听起来有点奇怪  - 是有点 嗯
- OK, that sounded a little weird.  - A little bit. Yeah.
你现在这个奇怪的表情 让我感觉也怪怪的了
And you're making a weird face, and that's making me feel weird.
重点是 我会好好看着你 就像…
The point is, I would watch you like someone...
不是爱人 我们没在恋爱 我不是说我爱你
Not love. We're not in love. I'm not saying I love you.
嘿 我爱你 管它的
Hey, I love you. Whatever.
但是我不是说我爱上了你 我是说…
But I'm not saying like I'm in love with you. I'm saying...
罗珊？Roxaroo？人呢
Roxanne? Roxaroo?
- 哇… 怎么回事？ - 嘿…
- Whoa... What?  - Hey...
回去工作 市民花钱不是让你们来玩的
Get back to work. The city doesn't pay you to loaf.
- 站住！ - 喔 你们要干嘛 伙计？
- Freeze!  - Whoa. What are you doing, guys?
是我啊！监狱长啊
It's me! It's the warden.
嘿！开门！
Hey! Open up!
不 你们这些笨蛋 他骗了我们
No, you fools. He's tricked us.
说对了
You were right.
我永远会是个大坏蛋
I'll always be a villain.
噢 好啊 帅哥 要搭便车吗？
Well, hello good-looking. Need a lift?
当然啦 你这条可爱小鱼
Certainly do, you fantastic fish, you.
- 你快上车吧  - 我自由了！
- Get in the car, you.  - I'm free!
是吗？
Right?
仆人 干得好啊 送我这块表
Nice work sending me the watch, Minion.
- 当然啦 头儿  - 冲啊！
- You got it, boss.  - Punch it!
好 举起你们的双手
All right, put your hands in the air.
女士们 先生们 你们的大都会侠来了！
Ladies and gentlemen, your Metro Man!
- 谁是你们的英雄？ - 大都会侠！
- Who's your man?  - Metro Man!
没错 大都会市市民！
Yeah, Metro City!
来一下 来吧 来一下
Gimme some. Come on. Give it now.
跟我来 来吧 祝福我吧 好了
Give it to me. Right on. Gimme the good stuff. All right.
嘿 大都会市
Hey, Metro City.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
大家现在声音小一点好吗
You know, you know, I just want to bring it down a bit.
孩子 小点声 谢谢 伙计
Boys, a little lower. Thank you, fellas.
我们来说点现实的
Let's get real for a moment.
对 没错 说得对
That's right. That's right. That's right.
虽然拥有一整个博物馆是超级棒 超级棒的事
Although getting a whole museum is super-cool, is super-cool,
但是你们知道 你们给我最大的荣誉是什么吗？
you want to know what the greatest honor you've given me is?
你们真的想知道吗？真的吗？
Do you really want to know? Really?
我告诉你们
I'll tell you.
你们给我最大的荣誉就是 让我为你们服务
The greatest honor you've given me is letting me serve you,
为大都会市无助的民众服务
the helpless people of Metro City.
每天快结束的时候
And at the end of every day,
我就经常问自己…
well, I often ask myself...
没了你们 我又将是谁？
who would I be without you?
- 我爱你 大都会侠！ - 我爱你们 每位市民
- I love you, Metro Man!  - And I love you, random citizen.
我告诉你哦 仆人 金窝银窝比不上自己的狗窝啊
I tell you, Minion. There's no place like evil lair.
头儿 我为您一直把这儿保持得阴冷潮湿
I've kept it cold and damp just for you, sir.
我看起来怎样 仆人？看起来很坏吧？
How do I look, Minion? Do I look bad?
特别令人毛骨悚然 头儿
Disgustingly horrifying, sir.
你真会说话
You always know what to say.
噢 头儿 这些中央机器人都想死你了
Oh, the brain-bots certainly missed you, sir.
你们想爸爸了吗？谁是邪恶的小机器人？
Did you miss your daddy? Who's a menacing little cyborg?
你是 没错 你是 不许咬人
You are. Yes, you are. No biting.
不行 不行 不行哦
No, no, no, no, no, no.
想要这个扳手？去追吧
You want the wrench? Go get the wrench.
- 噢 看看那儿  - 现在 我们继续嗨
- Oh, look at that.  - Now, back to laughing.
她醒了 快 开工吧
She's awake. Quick, to work.
荔枝小姐 我们又见面了
Miss Ritchi, we meet again.
你就不能洗一下那个袋子？
Would it kill you to wash the bag?
荔枝小姐 你可以随便尖叫
You can scream all you wish, Miss Ritchi.
没人能听到的
I'm afraid no one can hear you.
为… 为什么她不叫？
Wh... Why isn't she screaming?
荔枝小姐 你不介意的话 叫一下？
Miss Ritchi, if you don't mind?
像这样…
Like this...
不过这个 这个是很烂的女士叫法
But that's, that's a poor lady scream.
他叫得好些了
He's a little better.
是不是有什么讨厌的超级大坏蛋的网站
Is there some kind of nerdy super-villain web site
让你弄来这些特斯拉感应圈和闪闪亮的表盘？
where you get Tesla coils and blinky dials?
实际上 这些东西大多是专营店弄来的 就在…
Actually, most of it comes from an outlet store in...
不许答这个问题
Don't answer that.
- 罗马尼亚  - 不许！别说！
- Romania.  - Don't! Stop!
她这是运用自己记者的追问技巧
She's using her nosy reporter skills
从你意志薄弱的小脑瓜里挖出我们所有的秘密
on your weak-willed mind to find out all our secrets.
这种小把戏对我没用的…
Such tricks won't work on me...
- 请慢点说  - 小妖精
- Please talk slower.  - temptress.
什么秘密啊？一眼就看穿你了
What secrets? You're so predictable.
你说我好看穿？你说我好看穿？
Predictable? Predictable?
噢 你管这样容易看穿？
Oh, you call this predictable?
你那些短吻鳄吗 没错
Your alligators. Yes.
没错 我这一路上就想着会这样了
Yeah, I was thinking about it on the way over.
那这样呢？砰！到你脸上
What's this? Boom! In your face.
- 老把戏  - 不！看 看好了
- Cliche.  - No! Look, watch.
- 幼稚  - 震撼吧
- Juvenile.  - Shock and awe.
- 俗  - 噢 明明很吓人啊！
- Tacky.  - Oh, it's so scary!
- 见过了  - 那这个呢？
- Seen it.  - What's this one do?
臭显摆
Garish.
- 好吧 蜘蛛有创意  - 蜘蛛？
- OK, the spider's new.  - Spider?
是的 蜘… 蜘蛛
Yes. The... the spee-ider.
即使被它碰一下
Even the smallest bite from Arachnis deathicus
也会马上瘫痪…
will instantly paralyze...
快弄掉！咬到我了！
Get it off! It bit me!
算了吧你 超级大坏蛋 你的阴谋就没得逞过
Give it up, Megamind. Your plans never work.
不要浪费时间了 让你那穿紧身衣的男朋友来救你吧
Let's stop wasting time and call your boyfriend in tights, shall we?
我很荣幸为大都会侠展示他的新博物馆
It is with great pleasure that I present to Metro Man his new museum.
请
If you please.
- 大都会侠！ - 嘿！你挡住我孩子了
- Metro Man!  - Hey! My kid can't see.
- 超级大坏蛋！ - 噢 好啊 大都会侠
- Megamind!  - Oh, bravo, Metro Man.
嘘！
Boo!
我也会 嘘！
Yes, I can play along too. Boo!
早该知道你会来捣乱的
Should've known you'd try to crash the party.
哦 我可不只想捣乱
Oh, I intend to do more than crash it.
今天会是个让你和大都市永远铭记的日子
This is a day you and Metrocity shall not soon forget.
应该读大都会市
It's pronounced Metro City!
大同小异
Potato-tomato, potato-tomato.
大家都知道今天会是怎样一个结局: 那就是你进大牢
We all know how this ends: With you behind bars.
我好怕怕哦
I'm shaking in my custom baby seal leather boots.
你必须离开大都市 否则这将是你最后一次
You will leave Metrocity, or this will be the last
看到罗珊・罗奇
you ever hear of Roxanne Ritchi.
罗珊！别害怕 洛茜
Roxanne! Don't panic, Roxie.
- 我马上就来  - 是的 我不害怕
- I'm on my way.  - Yeah, I'm not panicking.
要阻止我 你得先找到我 大都会侠
In order to stop me, you need to find me first, Metro Man.
我们在废弃的天文台
We're at the abandoned observatory.
没有 我们不在那！
No, we're not!
别听她的 她疯了
Don't listen to her. She's crazy.
大都会侠来了 阁下
Metro Man approaching, sir.
等一下
Hold on a second.
哦 天哪！
Oh, good heavens!
你不知道你是在真正的天文台 是吗？
You didn't think you were in the real observatory, did you?
准备发射死亡之光 仆人
Ready the death ray, Minion.
死亡之光 正在准备
Death ray, readying.
这边 老朋友
Over here, old friend.
提醒你一下 你已经进入了我的圈套
In case you haven't noticed, you've fallen right into my trap.
你无法困住正义 它是一个想法 一种信念
You can't trap justice. It's an idea, a belief.
即使最忠诚的信仰也经不起时间的侵蚀
Even the most heartfelt belief can be corroded over time.
正义是一种永不锈蚀的金属
Justice is a non-corrosive metal.
但金属可以被扶仇之心熔化
But metals can be melted by the heat of revange.
应该读“复仇” 而它冰冷之时最有用
It's "revenge," and it's best served cold.
但很容易在邪恶的微波中变热
But it can be easily reheated in the microwave of evil.
我想你的微波过质保了
Well, I think your warranty is about to expire.
也许质保又延长了
Maybe I got an extended warranty.
如果你不合理使用产品 质保是无效的
Warranties are invalid if you don't use the product for its intended purpose.
噢 两位小女生 别斗嘴了 现在我可以回家了吗？
Oh, girls, girls, you're both pretty. Can I go home now?
当然 如果大都会侠可以经受全部的
Of course. That is, if Metro Man can withstand the full,
集中的太阳光炙烤！
concentrated power of the sun!
发射！
Fire!
奴才 发射啊？
Minion. Fire?
- 还在预热中 阁下  - 什么？
- It's still warming up, sir.  - Come again?
- 预热 阁下  - 预热？太阳还需要预热？
- Warming up, sir.  - Warming up? The sun is warming up?
还有一秒钟…
One second more and...
滴答 滴答 滴答
just tippy-tappy tippy-tap-tap, tip-top more,
- 马上…  - 不是吧！
- and we are ready in just...  - Honestly!
马上来救你 洛茜
On my way, Roxie.
我早告诉你把一切都准备好 说了多少次了
I told you to have things ready. I told you countless times.
你怎么总是责备我？
Why do you always blame me?
蜘蛛的毒性发作了
My spider bite is acting up.
你的阴谋破产了 接受现实吧
Your plan is failing. Just admit it.
是的 祝你好运吧
Yeah, good luck with that one.
你站哪一边的？
Whose side are you on?
- 失败的一边  - 谢谢
- The losing side.  - Thank you.
有人可以给我的绑票会员卡上盖个章吗？
Could someone stamp my Frequent Kidnapping Card?
所有人都知道 我们已经停止该促销活动了
You of all people know we discontinued that promotion.
- 大家再见了！ - 下周见？
- Ciao-ciao, all!  - Same time next week?
石灰！蟹块！
Dag! Crab nuggets!
- 他说什么了？ - “蟹块”？
- What did he just say?  - "Crab nuggets"?
海鲜薄饼！
Fackled fish cracker!
十秒钟后发射
Ten seconds to full power.
- 上帝啊 我出不去了  - 十…
- Good lord, I'm trapped.  - Ten...
- 怎么回事？ - 九…
- What kind of trickery is this?  - Nine...
- 你这个天才疯子  - 八…
- You mad genius.  - Eight...
- 你邪恶的天赋终见成效了  - 七…
- Your dark gift has finally paid off.  - Seven...
- 它… 它成了？ - 六…
- It... it has?  - Six...
显然这个屋顶铺上了铜片
This dome is obviously lined with copper.
- 是的？那又怎样？ - 主人…
- Yeah? So?  - Sir...
- 铜能摧毁我的能量  - 二…
- Copper drains my powers.  - Two...
- 你的弱点是铜？ - 一…
- Your weakness is copper?  - One.
- 你在开玩笑 是吧？ - 预热完毕
- You're kidding, right?  - Full power.
即使这个大英雄这回也难逃一死了
I don't think even he could survive that.
不要高兴太早
Well, let's not get our hopes up just yet.
- 看！ - 大都会侠！
- Look!  - Metro Man!
大都会侠
Metro Man.
大都会侠！
Metro Man!
- 你… 你成功了 主人  - 我成功了？
- You... You did it, sir.  - I did it?
他成功了
He did it.
- 我成功了？ - 他成功了
- I did it?  - He did it.
- 你成功了 主人  - 我成功了！
- You did it, sir.  - I did it!
- 你成功了！ - 我成功了！大都市归我了！
- You did it!  - I did it! Metrocity is mine!
- 你成功了 先生！ - 我成功了！是的 是我 是我！
- You did it, sir!  - I did it! Yeah, me, me!
- 是的 我成功了！ - 我俩！我俩成功了！
- Yes, I did it!  - Us! We both did it!
- 不是我俩！是我！ - 你的功劳
- Not us! I!  - You, a little more
- 比我大一点点 但是 讲点道理好吧！ - 我功劳比你大多了
- than me but still, come on!  - A lot more than you.
当他们颁奖时
When they're giving out the awards,
- 我会站在你身旁  - 什么奖？什么奖 为什么？
- I'm gonna be right there next to you.  - What awards? What awards, for what?
音乐！
Hit it!
把枪放下！
Drop 'em!
首先 来的人真多啊
First off, what a turnout.
太给力了！
How wild is this?
我只是把全宇宙最强大的人干掉了
All I did was eliminate the most powerful man in the universe.
-  有人提问题吗？尽管提  - 这边！ - 那个站后面的
-  Are there any questions? Go on.  - Yes!  - You in the back.
我相信大家都想知道 你想把我们和这个城市怎么样
I'm sure we'd all like to know what you plan to do with us and this city.
问得好 很高兴你问这个问题
Good, I'm glad you asked that.
想象一下你能想到的
Imagine the most horrible, terrifying,
最可怕 恐怖 邪恶的事
evil thing you can possibly think of,
再乘以… 六！
and multiply it... by six!
同时
In the meantime,
我希望你们继续过着你们普通人
I want you to carry on with the dreary, normal things
无聊的日常生活
you normal people do.
大家玩得开心 高兴点
Let's just have fun with this. Come on.
回见
And I will get back to you.
用力关门
Now slam the door really hard.
他们… 他们还能看见你
They... they can still see you.
- 现在呢？ - 胳膊肘
- Now?  - Your elbow's still in.
好了
Good.
邪恶霸王先生驾到
There he is, Mr. Evil Overlord
哦 仆人 你想过这一天吗？
Oh, Minion, did you think this day would ever come?
绝对没有 一点都没有 主人
No way. Not at all, sir.
从没 从来没有… 我的意思是…
Never. Never in a million... I mean...
- 我想过  - 看着这精致的装饰
- Yes, I did.  - Look at the intricate mouldings.
看到了 看到了
I'm looking. I'm looking.
这是什么？
And what's this?
像我们小窝的超大显示器
It's like one of the giant monitors in the lair.
但貌似只播一个台
But it seems to only carry one station.
噢 那个 先生 叫窗户
Oh, that, sir, is called a window.
- 窗户？ - 所有孩子都喜欢透过它朝外看
- Window?  - All the kids are looking through them.
我从没见过这么好的视野
I've never had a view before.
大都市 仆人 都是我的了
Metrocity, Minion, it's all mine.
如果我的父母现在能看见我就好了
If my parents could see me now.
主人 我相信他们正从邪恶的天堂朝这微笑呢
Sir, I'm sure they're smiling down from evil heaven.
现在假正经先生滚蛋了
And now that Mr. Goody Two-Shoes is out of the way,
我能拥有一切
I can have everything I want,
无人能挡！
and there's no one to stop me!
知道 知道
I know. I know.
口渴难耐 永不知足
Always thirsty, never satisfied.
你和我同命相连 漂亮的小鸟
I understand you, little well-dressed bird.
无为 空虚 整个就像在真空里 不是吗
Purposeless, emptiness. It's a vacuum, isn't it?
它是… 你的真空是怎样的？
It's... What's your vacuum like?
- 嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿！ - 现在不是时候 仆人
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!  - Not now, Minion.
我正在和这只瞎眼塑料玩具
I'm in a heated, existential discussion
激烈地探讨存在价值呢
with this dead-eyed, plastic desk toy.
出… 出什么问题了吗 主人？
Is... is something wrong, sir?
好好想想
Just think about it.
我们应有尽有
We have it all.
然而也一无所有
Yet, we have nothing.
一切都太轻松了
It's just too easy now.
对不起 我不明白 先生
I'm sorry, you've lost me, sir.
我意思是 我们成功了 对吗？
I mean, we did it, right?
你成功了 阁下
Well, you did it, sir.
是的 你很强调这一点
Yes, you've made that perfectly clear.
那为什么我觉得这么… 忧沉呢？
Then why do I feel so... mel-on-choly.
“忧沉”？
"Mel-on-choly"?
- 不开心  - 那好…
- Unhappy.  - Well...
那明天
What if tomorrow,
我们绑架罗珊・罗奇吧
we could go kidnap Roxanne Ritchi.
这事总让你兴奋
That always seems to lift your spirits.
好主意 仆人 但他走了 意义何在？
Good idea, Minion. But without him, what's the point?
- “他” 先生？ - 没什么
- "Him," sir?  - Nothing.
好 那我们… 需要考虑一下…
OK, all right. We'll just... that's something to consider...
他曾经总守护在我们身边 那么值得信赖
He was always there for us. Dependable.
也许我们习以为常了 也许
Perhaps we took him for granted. You know, maybe,
直到他逝去了 我们才真正明白他的价值
we never really know how good we have it until it's gone.
我们想你 大都会侠 我想你
We miss you, Metro Man. I miss you.
我只有一个问题想问超级大坏蛋:现在你开心吗？
And I have just one question for Megamind: Are you happy now?
罗珊・罗奇来自一个失去英雄的城市的报道
This is Roxanne Ritchi, reporting from a city without a hero.
接下来 你准备好做奴隶了吗？你所需知道的一切
Coming up next, are you ready to be a slave army? What you need to know.
接着… 把那包起来 送给孩子当圣诞礼物
And... wrap that up and give it to a child on Christmas,
- 因为我们做完了  - 好的 明天见 哈尔
- 'cause we're done.  - OK. See you tomorrow, Hal.
等等 洛茜 我家有个聚会
Wait. Roxie, I'm having a party at my house.
暂时忘却痛苦
It's gonna be, like, off the hook, or whatever.
希望你能参加 我找了个DJ
You should come over. I got a deejay,
租了个充气屋 备了美酒
rented a bouncy house, made a gallon of dip.
会很有意思的
It's gonna be sick.
噢 我… 我不知道 哈尔
Oh. I... I don't know, Hal.
我现在不想待在人多的地方
I don't really feel like being around a bunch of people.
不 不 不 最棒的正在此 聚会只有你和我两人
No, no, no, that's the best part. It'll just be like you and me.
哇 那… 那确实很吸引人 但是…
Wow. That... that's certainly very tempting, but...
我邀请了一名婚纱摄影师 只为万一我们
I did hire a wedding photographer. That's just in case we were like,
做了一些很疯狂的事 希望拍照留念
something crazy happened and we wanted a picture of it.
譬如 也许我们应该把这个 像回忆一样永久收藏  懂我意思吗？
Like, maybe we should have this for, like, ever. Like a memory, you know?
我还是不去了
I'm gonna pass.
而且我在这还有些工作要做
I have some work here that I need to do, anyway.
好吧 那星期四怎样？
Cool. So Thursday? Soft Thursday?
- 晚安 哈尔  - 那你算委婉地答应了
- Good night, Hal.  - That's a soft yes on Thursday.
我是不是有病啊？租了个充气屋？
What's wrong with me? Rented a bouncy house?
女生不喜欢充气屋
Chicks don't like bouncy houses.
他们喜欢小丑
They like clowns.
垃圾车！你伤了我的手指！
Stupid van! You broke my finger!
我犯了个可怕的错误
I've made a horrible mistake.
我本不想毁灭你的
I didn't mean to destroy you.
我的意思是 我想毁灭你
I mean, I meant to destroy you,
但我不认为我能做到
but I didn't think it would really work.
我们该怎么办？
What are we supposed to do?
没有你 邪恶肆无忌惮地横行于每个角落
Without you, evil is running rampant through the streets.
我已经厌倦了横行无忌
I'm so tired of running rampant through the streets.
当没有正义挺身而出的时候
What's the point of being bad
做坏人还有什么意思？
when there's no good to try and stop you?
得有人阻止超级大坏蛋
Someone has to stop Megamind.
- 嘿 我们马上关门了  - 你吓到我了
- Hey, we're closing soon.  - You scared me.
- 巴里 是吗？ - 伯纳德
- Barry, right?  - Bernard.
伯纳德 我只是… 好吧 我是在自言自语
Bernard. I was just... Well, I was talking to myself.
也许你会觉得我有点神经不正常
You probably think I'm a little bit nuts.
我不可以侮辱顾客
I'm not allowed to insult guests directly.
谢谢 只是… 伯纳德 我还要待几分钟
Thank you. Just... Bernard, I'll just be another minute.
好吧
OK.
谢谢
Thanks.
我准备了许多犯罪计划
I had so many evil plans in the works.
文盲光波
The illiteracy beam.
台风奶酪
Typhoon cheese.
机器羊
Robo-sheep.
我们已无法在这些战争中一决高下了
Battles we will now never have.
你知道的 我没能与你道别
You know, I never had the chance to say goodbye.
所以现在 在我摧毁这个地方之前
So it's good that we have this time now.
有这段时光真好
You know, before I destroy the place.
不是针对你 只是它唤起太多痛苦的记忆
Nothing personal, it just brings back too many painful memories.
有人吗？
Hello?
- 谁在那？ - 罗珊
- Hello?  - Roxanne.
- 这扮相太没品味了  - 扮相？
- That's a pretty tasteless costume.  - Costume?
超级大坏蛋的头没那么夸张
Megamind's head is not that grossly exaggerated.
你甚至做了他的脱水枪的山寨版 怎样…
And you even made a cheap replica of his dehydration gun. How...
嗨？谁在那？
Hello? Is someone there?
Hello? Who's there?
居然是你 伯纳德
It's just you, Bernard.
是的 当然是我 伯纳德
Yes. It's just me. Bernard.
嗯 多谢你让我待着
Well, thank you for letting me stay.
听着 如果我是你 两分三十七秒内我会离开这里
Look, I wouldn't stay here for more than two minutes and 37 seconds
我们要拆墙壁和天花板了
if I were you. We're having the walls and ceiling removed.
喔 听起来要搞大翻修
Wow, that sounds like quite the renovation.
那我要搭你的顺风车下去了
I guess I'll catch a ride down with you then.
我还在想 他能在最后关头逃出来
I kept thinking he was gonna do one of his last-minute escapes.
是啊 他相当擅长这些
Yeah. He was really good at those.
噢 如果这个世界有重置键就好了
Oh, if only the world had a reset button.
我研究过重置键
I've looked into the reset button.
科技无法办到
The science is impossible.
噢 伯纳德…
Oh, Bernard...
我不知道你有… 感触 你还好吗？
I didn't know you had... feelings. Are you OK?
大都会侠死了 那么现在没人可以挑战超级大坏蛋了
Metro Man's gone. And now there's no one left to challenge Megamind.
噢 拜托 伯纳德
Oh, come on, Bernard.
只要存在邪恶 正义就会奋起阻止它
As long as there's evil, good will rise up against it.
噢 希望如此
Oh, I wish.
我相信将会有人站出来制住超级大坏蛋的
I believe someone is gonna stand up to Megamind.
- 你真的这么想吗？ - 是的 我是说 就像他们说的那样
- You really think so?  - Yeah. I mean, it's like they say,
“英雄并非生来如此 他们可以制造出来”
"Heroes aren't born, they're made."
英雄可以制造出来 就是它！
Heroes can be made. That's it!
你要的只是正确的素材
All you need are the right ingredients.
- 是的 勇敢  - 是的
- Yeah. Bravery.  - Yes.
- 力量  - 必须的
- Strength.  - Of course.
- 果断  - 决绝！
- Determination.  - Imperative!
还要一点点DNA 噢 有了这些 谁都可以是英雄！
And a smidgen of DNA. Oh, with that, anyone can be a hero!
太棒了！
Yeah!
我们得赶紧离开！
I think we should run!
再见！
Bye!
我们该忘却过去了
Time to put the past behind us.
只有未来…
Only the future...
我靠太近了！这次我真的被吓到了
I'm too close! I'm genuinely scared right now.
希望没人看到这一幕！
I hope no one's seeing this!
创造一个英雄？等一下？你干嘛要这样做？
Create a hero? Wait, wait, what? Why would you do that?
这样就有人与我为敌了
So I have someone to fight.
仆人 我是个没有英雄对抗的坏蛋
Minion, I'm a villain without a hero.
无阳之阴
A yin with no yang.
无牛可斗的斗牛士
A bullfighter with no bull to fight.
换句话说 我没有目标
In other words, I have no purpose.
现在 问我要怎么做 来吧 问我！
Now, ask me how I'm going to do it. Go on! Ask!
你要怎么做？
How are you gonna do it?
我要赋予某人… 我还不知道是谁…
I'm going to give someone... I don't know who yet...
大都会侠的能力
Metro Man's powers.
我要把这个人训练成大都市的新英雄
I'm going to train that someone to become Metrocity's new hero.
看这里！过来！
Over here! Follow!
最后 我将与这个英雄进行
And then finally, I'm going to fight that hero
一场史诗级的正邪之战
in an epic battle of good and evil.
到时候一切都将回到原点…
Which will put everything back the way it was...
世界将变得幸福美好
when the world was perfect and rosy.
看 仆人 大都会侠的披风
Behold, Minion, Metro Man's cape.
凑近点看 告诉我你看到了什么
Look closely. Tell me what you see.
- 头皮屑？ - 是的 这是他的DNA
- Dandruff?  - Yes. It's his DNA.
由此 我们可以提取出大都会侠超能力的基因
From this, we'll extract the source of Metro Man's awesome power.
老大 我觉得这主意很烂
Sir, I think this is a bad idea.
是的 制造更厉害的英雄 这主意真够邪恶 真够烂啊
Yes! This is a very wickedly bad idea for the greater good of man.
但是我说它很烂是…
But I'm saying this is a kind of bad that...
好吧 也许从你非正常的眼光来看 这主意不错
OK, you might think is good in your bad perception,
但从正常眼光来看… 它真的挺烂的
but from a good perception it... it's just plain bad.
噢 你不懂何为好 何为坏
Oh, you don't know what's good for bad.
现在 我们有且只有这一发
Now, we have just one shot at this.
我们必须找到合适的目标 拥有高贵的心灵和思想的人
We must find a suitable subject, someone of noble heart and mind.
[注 入]
能将他人利益置于个人利益之上的人
Who puts the welfare of others above their own.
究竟是什么在叫？
What on Earth is that?
像是从那儿发出来的 老大
It seems to be emanating from there, sir.
姨好
Ollo.
是“你好”啦
It's "Hello."
你好？这样说吗？
Hello? Like that?
- 伯纳德 我是罗珊  - 是罗珊
- Bernard, it's Roxanne.  - It's Roxanne.
我只是想跟你说声感谢 感谢你前些天给我打气
I just wanted to thank you for inspiring me the other day.
- 噢 你也鼓励了我  - 好的！
- Oh, you inspired me too.  - Great!
我们应该起来抵抗超级大坏蛋 告诉他不能任意摆布我们
It's time we stood up to Megamind and show him he can't push us around.
噢 真的吗？她太可爱了
Oh, really? She's so cute.
我已经追踪到他了
I'm already hot on his trail.
- 怎么说？ - 老大？
- And what gives you that idea?  - Sir?
我已经找到他的秘密藏身处了
I just found his secret hideout.
她是怎么找到我的藏身处的？！
How did she find my hideout?!
你是怎么找到他的藏身处的？
How did you find his hideout?
全大都会市只有这栋建筑的屋顶上有假观望台
This is the only building in Metro City with a fake observatory on the roof.
好吧 她绝不可能发现秘密入口
OK. There's no way she'll find the secret entrance.
这儿有个门垫写着“必密入口”！
There's a doormat here that says "Secrit Entrance"!
- 仆人！ - 我都忘了它在那里了
- Minion!  - I kept forgetting where it was.
她会发现我们所有秘密的！
She'll discover all our secrets!
- 噢 不！ - 你这个低智商的科学创造物！
- Oh, no!  - You dim-witted creation of science!
- 什么？ - 什么？噢 不 不是说你 罗珊
- What?  - What? Oh, no, not you, Roxanne.
不 我只是在对着… 我妈的骨灰盒吼
No, I was just yelling at my... mother's urn.
别乱动 我马上到
Don't do anything. I'll be right there.
罗珊呢？
Roxanne?
噢 不 又来！
Oh no, not again!
罗珊吗？
Roxanne?
很高兴你来了 等等 你怎么来得这么快？
I'm glad you're here. Wait, how did you get here so fast?
呃 你打来电话时 我… 我刚好竞走经过这里
Well, I... I happened to be speed walking nearby when you called.
穿着西装？
In a suit?
这是所谓的… 正装竞走 但这不重要
It's called... formal speed walking, but that's not important.
我在前面开路吧 这条路看起来很刺激
I better take the lead. This way looks exciting.
不 上面写着“出口”
No, it says "Exit."
“寻刺激之口”的缩写不正是它吗？
Which is the abbreviation for "exciting," right?
这才是金矿！
This is the mother lode!
- 哇 快看呐  - 哇
- Wow. Just look at this thing.  - Wow.
你知道吗 有你帮忙我可以破译所有这些东西
You know, I really could use your help in deciphering all this.
- 是吗？ - 你是个专家
- Really?  - You're an expert
- 超级大坏蛋的所有事 你都在行 对吗？ - 是的 没错
- on all things Megamind, right?  - Yes. Right.
我们一起 可以识破他关于这座城市的诡计 及时阻止他
Together, we could figure out his plan for the city and stop it.
- 你加入吗？ - 噢 很有意思！
- Are you in?  - Oh, what fun!
我就是想听这句话
That's what I want to hear.
仆人 指令: 让中央机器人们进来
Minion, Code: Send In The Brain-bots.
你知道 呼叫的意义在于…
You know, the whole point of a code is...
噢 指令: 照做就是了 仆人
Oh, Code: Just Do lt, Minion.
闯入者！闯入者！闯入者！
Intruder! Intruder! Intruder!
- 是我 你们这些笨蛋！ - 伯纳德！
- It's me, you fools!  - Bernard!
是老爸我！
It's Daddy!
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
- 你对伯纳德做了什么？ - 噢 伯纳德？噢 是的
- What have you done with Bernard?  - Oh, Bernard? Oh, yes.
我正对他做很可怕的事情
I'm doing horrible things to that man.
例如激光啊 钉刺神马的 希望我别上迷了
I don't want to get into it, but lasers, spikes.
不 求你了！不！别用激光 别用钉刺！
No, please! No! Not the lasers and the spikes!
- 你知道钻孔机的  - 噢 不！别用钻孔机！
- You know the drill.  - Oh, no! Not the drill!
- 放开他 要不然…  - 不然怎样？
- Let him go or...  - Or what?
不然我就试试这把怪枪有什么用
Or I'm gonna find out what this weird-looking gun does.
不 别开枪！别开枪！
No, don't shoot! Don't shoot that gun!
我马上去救他
I'll just go get him.
- 放开我 你这个魔鬼！ - 决不！
- Unhand me, you fiend!  - Never!
他的力量太强了！
His strength's too much!
噢 我经常锻炼身体！
Oh, I work out!
呃 很有效啊！你太有力了
Well, it's really paying off! You're so fit,
天赐神力啊
and strangely charismatic.
你还好吗？
Are you OK?
我尽力了 但是他太强大了
I did my best, but he's too fantastic.
给我 我帮你拿这把沉重的枪
Here. Let me carry that heavy gun for you.
我来掩护
I got us covered.
- 放手 这是我的！ - 伯纳德 快跑！
- Let go. It's mine!  - Bernard, run!
罗珊你在哪？
Roxanne?
- 你会弄坏它的！ - 把它给我！
- You're going to break it!  - Give it to me!
噢 不！
Oh, no!
罗珊是你吗？！
Roxanne?!
这到底是谁？
Who on Earth is that?
- 救命！ - 罗珊！
- Help!  - Roxanne!
伯纳德！你说对了 那扇门很刺激
Bernard! You were right about that door being exciting.
- 闯入者！闯入者！ - 这边走
- Intruder! Intruder!  - This way.
闯入者！闯入者！闯入者！
Intruder! Intruder! Intruder!
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
这能拦住他们 给！
This'll stop them. Here!
有点过份了 不是吗？
Seems a bit extreme, doesn't it?
- 扔出去就行了！ - 老爸对不起你们
- Just throw it!  - Daddy's sorry.
- 喔 这相当刺激  - 是啊
- Wow. That was really exciting.  - Yeah.
- 你在里面很勇敢  - 我知道
- You were very strong in there.  - I know.
我从没见过谁能这么对付他 除了大都会侠
I've never seen anyone but Metro Man stand up to him like that.
- 发生什么事了？ - 哈尔 怎么了？
- What's going on?  - Hal, what happened?
我觉得有只蜜蜂飞进了我的鼻子
I think a bee flew up my nose.
我正想发动正面攻势来解救你
I was just about to make my frontal assault to rescue you,
但是大约有五十个忍者袭击了我 所以我不得不痛扁他们
but like 50 ninjas tried to attack me, so I had to beat 'em all up,
而且我 我让… 他们全部哭爹喊娘
and I did, and I... They were all, like, crying and stuff...
- 喔 勇敢的人 不是吗？ - 你是谁？
- Wow, a brave one, isn't he?  - Who are you?
噢 这… 这是伯纳德 他是我的搭档
Oh, thi... this is Bernard. He's my partner.
- 搭档？ - 是的 是的 搭档
- Partner?  - Yes. Yes. Partner.
噢 听着 “搭档” 我是她的搭档 她不知道她在说什么
Well, look, "partner," I'm her partner. She doesn't know what she's saying.
她刚从一次痛苦经历中走出来
She's been through a traumatic experience.
我得送他回家 再次感谢 伯纳德
I'd better take him home. Thanks again, Bernard.
我明天给你打电话 拍档
I'll call you tomorrow, partner.
好 好的 我很荣幸
Yeah, OK. I'd like that.
这对大家来说很怪
That was weird for everybody,
因为你突然拥抱了他 而不是我
'cause you accidentally hugged him instead of me.
老大？老大！
Sir? Sir!
指令: 你弄清他是谁了吗？
Code: Did You Find Out Who It Was?
指令: 把车开来
Code: Get The Car.
收到指令: 马上来 老大
Code: Right Away, Sir.
- 拜拜！ - 明天见 哈尔
- Bye-bye!  - See you tomorrow, Hal.
我会把门开着 以便你等会儿来探望我
I'll leave the door unlocked in case you want to check on me later.
这个被我们灌输了神力的人是谁呢？
Who is this man we've infused with godlike power?
呃 老大 他叫哈尔・斯图尔特 二十八岁
Well, sir, his name's Hal Stewart. He's 28 years old.
无不良记录 准确的说 根本没有资料
No criminal record. Actually no records at all.
显然这个人一事无成
Apparently this man hasn't accomplished anything.
暂时没有 仆人 暂时… 没有
Not yet, Minion. Not... yet.
今天还能更糟点么？
Could this day get anymore fun-tastic?
这样 在错误扩大之前 我去把他的能量抽出来
So, I will just go ahead and diffuse him since this is clearly a mistake.
不 仆人！现在发生的事无比神奇
No, Minion! There's something much more powerful at work here.
这不是错误 这是命中注定
This is no mistake. It's destiny.
哈尔・斯图尔特！准备好接受你的命运吧！
Hal Shtewart! Prepare for your destiny!
哈尔？哈尔・斯图尔特呢？
Hal? Hal Shtewart?
- 嘿！在床里！ - 我这样说对吗？
- Hey! In the bed!  - Am I saying it right?
是“斯图尔特”啦
"Stewart."
是抢劫吗？
Is this a robbery?
走廊另一边那个太太比我有钱多了
'Cause the lady across the hall has way better stuff than me.
噢 看呐 这是哈尔・斯图尔特 快 喷雾
Oh, look, it's Hal Stewart. Quick, the spray.
用光了
All out.
- 噢 用“忘了我”棍子  - 噢 对哦
- Well, use the Forget-Me Stick.  - Oh, right.
好好看看他
Just look at him.
不 依我看 他没有个英雄样
No, he doesn't look quite the hero-type to me.
噢 你可真够让人讨厌的
Oh, you're such a pill, Minion.
东西好坏不在材料
A potter couldn't ask for finer clay.
我闻到了英雄的味道
I smell a hero.
我闻到东西烧着的味道
I smell something burning.
我想它起作用了 就位！就位！
I think it's working. Places! Places!
就位！就位！快就位
Places! Places! Places.
你的变装呢？
Do you have your disguise?
怎么了？
What?
哦 你看起来很棒
Oh, you look fantastic.
觉醒吧 我的荣耀之作
Rise my glorious creation.
觉醒吧 来爸爸这
Rise, and come to Papa.
- 这是怎么了？ - 放轻松 孩子
- What's going on?  - Easy my child.
- 你是谁？ - 我为了教你正义 荣誉
- Who are you?  - I sent you to this planet
和高尚的品德 而将你送到这个星球
to teach you about justice, honor, and nobility.
我是你的父亲
I am your father.
那你就算是我的太空爸爸？
So you're like my space dad?
对 我就算是你的太空爸爸了
Yeah, I'm like your space dad.
那你又是什么？
And you are what?
我是你的太空后妈
I'm your space stepmom.
我最近做了点美容
I've had some work done recently.
这是在做梦吗？
Is this some kind of dream?
这是梦想成真
This is a dream come true.
你已被赐予深不可测的力量
You've been blessed with unfathomable power.
- 什么样的力量？ - 深不可测
- What kind of power?  - Unfathomable.
就是深… 没有深度的
It's unf... without fathom.
是的 我们是来引导你
Yeah. We've come to guide you
成为大都市的新英雄
on your path to be Metrocity's new hero
并与超级大坏蛋的超级才智搏斗
and battle the super-genius of Megamind.
我知道这一时有点难以接受
I know this is a lot to take in.
你可能需要花几个月才能接受
It may take months for you to come to grips.
不可能吧！
No freaking way!
我还没说完呢
I wasn't finished.
我要当英雄了！
I'm gonna be a hero!
看吧 仆人 他太合适了！
See, Minion, he's perfect!
预备… 开始！
And... action!
- 来人啊 救救我！ - 我没事！
- Someone help me!  - I'm OK!
你… 大坏蛋！
You... Bad!
我的邪恶之火正熊熊燃烧
The flames of my evil burn bright.
现在换你对我说点狠话
Now you say something cool back at me.
看呐 一点都不疼 甚至都没感觉
Look. It doesn't even hurt. Don't even feel it.
不 不 不 不 不 肚子朝下 手抬起来 像大都会侠那样
No, no, no, no, no. Stomach down, hands up. Like Metro Man.
- 喔啊！等等！ - 小心
- Whoa! Wait!  - Watch out.
他简直无可救药！无可救药！
He's hopeless. Hopeless!
- 或许我们应该换个策略  - 你真这么想？
- Maybe we should change tactics.  - You think so?
哦 你应该了解男孩们
Oh, you know how boys are.
他们喜欢玩电子游戏
They love video games.
- 我可以把几个零件组装一下  - 等不及了
- I could throw a few parts together.  - Can't wait.
大笑吧 再来个笑脸
LOL. Smiley face.
等不及要干什么 老大？
Can't wait for what, sir?
那故事太好笑了
That was such a funny story.
还有 讲得也很精彩
And brilliantly told, by the way.
好吧 现在换你讲
OK, now you tell one.
伯纳德 我从来不知道你这么风趣
Bernard, I never knew you were so funny.
而我也从来没听到你这样大笑
And I never heard you laugh before.
嗯 很久没大笑过了 感觉很好
Yeah, it's been a while. Feels pretty good.
开始
And action.
搞定！
Gotcha!
- 你不经常出门吧？ - 哦 真好玩！
- You don't get out much, do you?  - Oh, what fun!
我小时候常常和妈妈来这里
I used to come here with my mother when I was a kid.
这是我最喜欢做的事情之一
It was one of my favorite things to do.
现在再看这 就是个垃圾场
Now look at it. It's a dump.
头 我们为什么要打扫城市？
Why are we cleaning up the city, sir?
嗯 我们也不想在垃圾场 和我们的新英雄开战吧？
Well, we don't want to battle our new hero in a dump now, do we?
它们全变回原样了 但这是怎么回事？为什么会这样？
They're all back. But how? Why?
也许超级大坏蛋并不是那么坏吧
Maybe Megamind isn't so bad after all.
就是这样
That's it.
自由飞翔吧 我漂亮的小鸽子！
Be free, my beautiful dove!
好吧 好吧
OK, OK.
大都会侠跟我 从来就不是一对
Metro Man and I were never a couple.
- 但我以为你们俩…  - 我知道 大家都以为
- But I thought you two were...  - I know. Everybody did.
只是… 其实他不是我喜欢的类型
It's just... Well, he was never really my type.
真的？
Really?
好了 现在换你跟我说了
OK, now you tell me something.
说你从没跟别人说过的事
Something you've never told anyone.
嗯 在鞋… 学校…
Well, in sh... school...
其他孩子都不喜欢我
none of the other kids really liked me.
无论什么事 我都是落单的那个
I was always the last one picked for everything.
如果我们上的是同一所学校就好了
It's too bad that we didn't go to the same school.
哈尔 我认为你已经准备好了
Hal, I think you're ready for this.
- 给我儿子的？ - 不是
- Do I have a son?  - No.
你真会搞笑
You make me laugh.
这是有弹性的 是给你的
It stretches. It's for you.
嘿 T代表什么啊？
Hey, what's the T stand for?
太阳神(英文由T开头)
Titan.
“太阳神”？那是什么意思？
"Titan"? What's that supposed to mean?
是我唯一能想到的贯耳之名
It was the only name I could trademark.
哈尔 你生命中有比较特殊的人吗？
Do you have someone special in your life, Hal?
没 还没有 不过… 有个真的 真的很漂亮的女孩
No, not yet. But... there's this really, really good-looking one
我最近一直在关注她
I've got my eye on currently.
那很好啊
That's very good.
- 浪漫爱情是很鼓舞人的  - 我听说也是
- Romance is very inspiring.  - That's what I hear.
你只需救她一次 她就是你的了
All you have to do is save her and she'll be yours.
- 谁想要西班牙油条？ - 我要！
- Who wants churros?  - I do!
- 我要 嗯 谢谢 太空后妈  - 发油条啦
- I do, yeah. Thanks, Space Stepmom.  - Churros all the way around.
我数到三 拔出你们的油条
On the count of three, unsheathe your churro.
一 二 三！
One, two, three!
致太阳神！
To Titan!
明天 你将迎战超级大坏蛋 整个城市将铭记住你的名字
Tomorrow, you will fight Megamind, and the city will know your name.
城市的公园恢复了往日的美丽
The city's parks restored to their original glory,
街道从未如此安全 银行重新开业
the streets the safest they've been, the banks reopened.
莫非超级大坏蛋出了什么事？
Has something happened to Megamind?
难道有人驯服了这头怪兽？
Has someone tamed this monster?
持审慎乐观态度 且处于愉悦的困扰中的
This is Roxanne Ritchi, cautiously optimistic,
罗珊・罗奇报道
and pleasantly confused.
嗯 你今晚貌似心情不错啊 老大
Well, you seem in a very good mood tonight, sir.
噢 对啊 这要花多久 仆人？
Oh, yes. How long is this going to take, Minion?
只要再改几处 老大 我马上将做好
Just a few alterations, sir, and I will be done
您有史以来最令人恐惧的披风！
with your most terrifying cape yet!
我要给它取名为…
I'm calling it...
黑暗眼镜蛇…
the Black Mamba...
黑暗眼镜蛇 很好
Black Mamba. Perfect.
天 我要迟到了 我得走了
Gosh, I am running late. I have to go.
什么？你… 你要去哪 老大？
What? Where... where are you going, sir?
明早 我们还要跟太阳神进行首次战斗
We have our debut battle with Titan tomorrow morning.
我们还没测试你的大战斗套装呢
We haven't even tested your big battle suit yet.
那些小问题你处理就好 仆人 我得… 赶快去帮人跑趟腿
You attend to the details, Minion. I have to... run a quick errand.
你从不干跑腿这事的
You don't run errands.
- 今个是怎么了？ - 什么？
- What's going on here?  - What?
哦 等等
Oh, wait a minute.
你是不是喷了让・保罗・戈尔捷的男士香水？
Are you wearing Jean Paul Gaultier's Pour Homme?
只不过是我的天然麝香 车钥匙呢？
It's just my natural musk. Now, where are the car keys?
这事跟荔枝小姐有关 对吧？
This is about Ms. Ritchi, isn't it?
你要跟她约会
You're going on a date with her.
不 我的核心助手 别瞎想了
No, my main man. Get out of town.
哦 坏了 这下可不好 你已经爱上她了
Oh, this is bad. This is bad. You've fallen in love with her.
你忘了你的身份 仆人 给我钥匙
You are forgetting your place, Minion. Now give me the keys.
如果罗珊发现你的真实身份怎么办？
What happens when Roxanne finds out who you really are?
她不会发现的 这是骗人的重点
She will never find out. That's the point of lying.
说实话 如果我不了解你
Honestly, if I didn't know any better,
我会以为你是头一天当坏人
I'd think this was your first day of being evil.
不行！
No!
这事就到此为止了
This has gone far enough!
哦 这么做还真是成熟！
Oh, that was really grown-up!
老大 老大 求你了 这是为你自己好
Sir, sir, please. It's for your own good.
哦 你知道什么啊？
Oh, what do you know?
我知道的可能不多 但有点我很确定:
I may not know much, but I do know this:
坏人得不到女主角
The bad guy doesn't get the girl.
也许我不想再当坏人了
Maybe I don't want to be the bad guy anymore.
你听到我说了！
You heard me!
你是谁？
Who are you?
- 现在 给我钥匙！ - 不！
- Now, give me the keys!  - No!
我活着的唯一目的就是照顾好你
My sole purpose in life is to look after you.
嗯 我不需要你照顾我
Well, I don't need you to look after me.
你在说… 你在说什么？你不需要我？
What are you s... what are you saying? You don't need me?
我说明白吧 指令: 我不需要你
Let me make it clear. Code: I Don't Need You.
你知道吗？你知道吗？
You know what? You know what?
收到指令: 那我就收拾东西走人！
Code: I'll Just Pack My Thing And Go!
- 指令：随你！ - 收到指令：也随你！
- Code: Fine!  - Code: Fine Back!
- 哼 祝你约会好运！ - 我会的！
- Well, good luck on your date!  - I will!
- 那话不作数！ - 我就知道！
- That doesn't even make any sense!  - I know!
我知道就差一点了 我能感觉到
I know I am so close. I can feel it.
好吧 好吧 我只需要后退一步
OK, OK. I just have to take a step back.
等等
Wait a minute.
“太阳神”
"Titan."
- 太阳神是什么？- 我的超级耳朵在燃烧
- What's a Titan?  - My super-ears are burning.
我通常只听到罪犯的声音 你最近没捣蛋吧？
I usually just hear criminals. You haven't been naughty, have you?
我跟你闹着玩呢 我跟你闹着玩呢
I'm totally messing with you. I'm totally messing with you.
- 我叫太阳神  - 太阳神
- The name's Titan.  - Titan.
是你的绝对酷毙了的个人英雄卫士
Your very own heroic guardian of pure awesome.
你叫什么名字？开玩笑的 我了解你的一切
What's your name? Just kidding. I know everything about you.
还有我… 我带了些花来
And I... And I brought some flowers.
不知道你喜欢什么 所以就 全拿来了
Didn't know what you liked, so I just grabbed, you know, all of them.
好吧 你不喜欢花？那好 别管花了
OK. You don't like flowers? OK, forget the flowers.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
觉得咱俩也许可以来点环城小飞行
Thought maybe we could go for a little flight around town.
互相了解一下
Get to know each other first.
你肯定很兴奋吧
This must be very thrilling for you.
你以为你在干什么啊？！
What do you think you're doing?!
哦 我进度太快了？你说的可能没错
Oh, am I moving too fast? You're probably right.
我应该先救你几次 然后再搞浪漫
I should just rescue you a few times before we get all romantic.
救了你啦
Saved ya.
有我这么个大英雄在 你真幸运
You are lucky to have such a great hero here.
- 你敢再…  - 哦 不！来人帮帮忙啊！
- Don't you ever...  - Oh, no! Somebody do something!
哦 对了 对了 笨呐 我来了 我来了
Oh, right, right, duh. I gotcha. I gotcha.
刚才够惊险的 你差点就死了
That was a close one. You almost died,
- 但我救了你  - 有楼！
- but I saved you.  - Building!
接住啦！对不起 你刚才说什么？
Gotcha! I'm sorry. What were you saying?
我救你的声音太大 没听到你说什么
I couldn't hear you over the sound of me saving your life.
放我下来！快点！
Put me down! Right now!
好吧 好吧 等一下
OK, all right. All right, hold on.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
我大概有点 有点 为你疯狂
I suppose I'm a, I'm a little crazy, about you.
你到底是谁啊？
Who are you, really?
哦 对了 好 准备大吃一惊吧 小淑女
Oh, right. Well, prepare to have your mind blown, little lady.
- 哒哒  - 哈尔？
- Ta-da.  - Hal?
对 是不是很棒？现在没什么能把我们分开了
Yeah. Isn't this great? Now there's nothing keeping us apart.
- 不 一点都不棒  - 哇哦 第一次吵架
- No. It's not great.  - Wow. Our first fight.
太像一对了 咱们就跟老夫老妻一样
This is so us. We're like an old married couple.
听着 没有“咱们”好吗？永远也不会有“咱们”
Look, there is no "us," OK? There will never be an "us."
但是… 我有超能力了
But... I have powers.
我还有披风 我是好人
I have a cape. I'm the good guy.
你是好人 哈尔 但你不明白
You are a good guy, Hal, but you don't understand.
- 我们得搞清楚为什么…  - 不 不 这…
- We need to find out why...  - No, no. This...
- 哈尔 深呼吸  - 这样不对！
- Hal, just take a deep breath  - This isn't right!
- 先听我说句话  - 你应该跟我在一起！
- And listen to me for a moment.  - You're supposed to be with me!
我只是想警告你 哈尔
I'm trying to warn you, Hal.
是太阳神 是太阳神 不是哈尔！
It's Titan! It's Titan, not Hal!
- 伯纳德  - 罗珊 来了啊
- Bernard.  - Roxanne.
- 抱歉我迟到了 - 哇哦 你的发型看起来很刺激
- Sorry I'm late.  - Wow, your hair looks exciting.
这可不是今晚唯一的刺激
Not the only exciting development of the night.
超级大坏蛋创造了一个新英雄 我知道为什么
Megamind's created a new hero, and I know why.
现在都说得通了 他怀念有人扁他的日子
It all makes sense now. He missed getting his butt kicked,
于是他创造了一个新英雄
so he created a new hero
- 来帮他扁自己  - 对
- to kick it for him.  - Yeah.
但他为什么要挑哈尔呢？
But why would he pick Hal?
挑谁也比挑哈尔好啊
Hal is the worst possible person you could pick.
哇哦 我有点不懂了
Wow. That's a lot to take in.
这事把我搞糊涂了
It boggles my mind.
我也很糊涂 不过 我相信我们会弄明白
I am extremely boggled. You know, I'm sure we'll get
到底谁要扁谁
to the bottom of who's kicking whose butt.
不过同时 咱们也享受一下彼此的陪伴吧
But in the meantime, let's enjoy each other's company.
对不起 伯纳德 当然 你说得没错
I'm sorry, Bernard, of course, you're right.
你知道 我说得太多了
You know, I could use a breather.
敬伯纳德
To Bernard,
在我极度混乱的世界中 他是唯一正常的人
for being the only normal thing in my crazy, upside-down world.
敬… 正常的人
To... being normal.
- 罗珊？ - 嗯？
- Roxanne?  - Yes?
假如说 我不是那么正常
Say I wasn't so normal.
比如说 我是秃顶 而且肤色是
Let's say I was bald and had the complexion of,
三原色中很流行的那种 我随便说说 没有特指谁
of a popular primary color, as a random, nonspecific example.
- 你还会喜欢和我在一起吗？ - 当然！
- Would you still enjoy my company?  - Of course!
人不可貌相 海水不可斗量
You don't judge a book by its cover or a person from the outside.
听你这么说 我就放心了
That's a relief to hear.
评论一个人 要看他的行动
You judge them based on their actions.
呃 那也很片面啊 不是吗？
Well, that seems kind of petty, don't you think?
怎么了？怎么了？
What? What?
别看我！只是技术故障！
Don't look at me! Just a technical glitch!
先别看！好了 没事了
Don't look yet! Well, never mind that.
好了
OK.
我们说到哪儿了？
Where were we?
- 你…  - 等等 等等
- You...  - Now, now, hold on.
原来是你！
You!
请让我解释！
I can explain!
你刚刚说的话 都不算数吗？
What about everything you just said?
不能以貌取人的啊？
About judging a book by its cover?
对 我们就得看本质 不是吗？
Well, let's take a look at the contents then, shall we?
你毁了大都会侠 霸占了这座城市
You destroyed Metro Man, you took over the city,
现在 你骗得了我的关心！
and then, you actually got me to care about you!
你怎么这样坏？竟然耍我？
Why are you so evil? Tricking me?
你究竟想得到什么啊？
What could you possibly hope to gain?
等等 我不信
Wait a minute. I don't believe this.
你真的以为 我会和你在一起吗？
Do you really think that I would ever be with you?
不是
No.
好吧 仆人！你说得没错！
OK, Minion! You were right!
是我… 是我错了！
I was... less right!
我们应该继续干我们所擅长的… 使坏
We should stick to what we're good at... being bad.
仆人 在吗？
[正义与邪恶]
你 去那儿！
You there!
对 就是你
Yeah, you.
把黑色眼镜蛇披风拿来
Bring out the Black Mamba.
好了 太阳神 等着被我打败吧
OK, Titan. It's time to go down in style.
听说又有新的英雄 想挑战我的邪恶啊
I hear there's a new hero who dares challenge my evil.
那个叫太阳神的呢？
Where is the one they call Titan?
有种你就来啊！
Challenge me if you dare!
噢 不 要撞坏了！
Oh no. We're gonna crash!
真是尴尬啊
This is embarrassing.
真是太不体谅人 愚蠢…
Of all the inconsiderate, bone-headed...
不负责任 野蛮…
irresponsible, rude...
不专业 就是这样！
unprofessional, that's what this is!
大都会侠会让我久等吗？
Would Metro Man have kept me waiting?
当然不会！他可是超专业的！
Of course not! He was a pro!
嘿 超级大坏蛋！我正要去找你呢
Hey, Megamind! You're actually the guy I want to see.
还有 我这里有门的
Also, there's a door here.
你知道我等你等了多久吗？
Do you have any idea how long I waited for you?
不 不 不 我完全明白你在说什么
No, no, no, I totally understand what you're saying.
你能先闭嘴吗 等我打通了这关再说
Could you just, just shut up for one second. I'm trying to beat this level.
你到底有没有想过出来和我挑战啊？
Were you even planning on showing up?
这是什么？
What's this?
你从哪儿弄的？
Where did you get all this stuff?
不是我的
It doesn't belong to me.
- 偷来的？ - 很酷 是吧？
- You stole it?  - Pretty cool, right?
- 不 不 不 不！你可是个英雄啊！ - 做英雄是失败者的游戏！
- No, no, no, no! You're a hero!  - Being a hero is for losers!
英雄总是不停地工作 一周无休的 为的是什么啊？
It's work, work, work, 24/7, and for what?
我本来想跟她约会 表白的
I only took the gig to get the girl,
但罗珊却不想和我有任何瓜葛
and it turns out Roxanne doesn't want anything to do with me.
- 你是说罗珊・罗奇？ - 没错！罗珊・罗奇！
- Roxanne Ritchi?  - Yeah! Roxanne Ritchi!
我看到她在和一个书呆子吃饭
I saw her having dinner and making googly eyes
还和他眉来眼去！
at some intellectual dweeb!
竟然有人敢打扰我的计划？
Who needs all that noise?
所以我想我们应该合作
That's why I think we should team up.
你… 等等… 什么？
You... wait... what?
以我的能力 再加上你的聪明才智
With my power, and your big-headedness,
- 我们可以统治这个城市！ - 你想合作？
- we could rule the city!  - You want to team up?
我还设计了新服装 你看？
I even drew up some new costume designs, see?
- 设计服装？ - 你脑袋聪明
- Costume designs?  - You'd be the brains,
因此 你的衣服有个小脑袋
so you'd get a little brain,
还要配上眼镜之类的
wearing glasses on your costume, or something.
既然我很酷 我就有 比如
And since I'm the cool one, I'd have, like,
两把厉害的剑…
two tanks swordfighting...
真不敢相信
I can't believe you.
所有你的才能 你的能力
All your gifts, all your powers,
你… 你竟然用来为自己牟利
and you... you squander them for your own personal gain.
- 没错！ - 不行！我才是坏蛋！
- Yes!  - No! I'm the villain!
你是好人！我才应该干坏事
You're the good guy! I do something bad,
你应该来抓我！我是为此才创造你的啊
and you come and get me! That's why I created you.
是吗 好吧 你这个傻瓜 太空爸爸告诉我…
Yeah, right. You're nuts. Space dad told me...
听着 我就是你的太空爸爸！
Look, I'm your space dad!
你应该向大都会侠学学
You should be more like Metro Man.
- 你耍我？ - 噢 不喜欢吗？
- You tricked me?  - Oh, don't like that?
不止呢
Well, there's more.
我还是那个和罗珊约会的书呆子呢
I'm also the intellectual dweeb dating Roxanne.
- 不会吧  - 我们还热吻了呢！
- No.  - And we were smooching up a storm!
要是让我抓到你 我就…
When I get my hands on you, I'm gonna...
对！对 我知道！将我绳之于法吧
Yes! Yes, I know! Bring me to justice.
哦 天啊 好久都没这样了
Oh God, how I've missed this.
英雄总是先发制人
And the hero strikes the first blow.
而坏蛋则是后发制人！
But evil returns with a backhand!
太棒了！
Yes!
出来啊 你个懦夫！
Come out, you little freak!
我想看看你被痛扁的样子！
I want to see what that big brain looks like on the pavement!
你连最简单的伎俩都应付不过来！
You fell for the oldest evil trick in the book!
你这个蓝色的白痴！
You little blue twerp!
准备好了！
En garde!
哦 这样才对嘛！
Oh, now that's the spirit!
躲闪！出击！再躲！
Parry! Thrust! Parry again!
现在我们终于要正式开战了！
Now it's time for some witty back and forth banter!
你先来！
You go first!
好吧！听着 你这样我可没办法！
OK! Look, I'm not sure where to go with that!
这一击 是因为你抢了我的女朋友！
This one's for stealing my girlfriend!
这一击 是因为你假扮太空爸爸耍我！
This one's for Space Dad making a fool out of me!
还有 超级大坏蛋 这一击 是为了太空后妈！你骗了她！
And, Megamind, this one's for Space Stepmom! You lied to her!
不错嘛 我觉得你打得真的非常 非常棒
Well done. I thought that battle went really, really well.
- 我是说 我还想说明几点  - 说明？
- I mean, I have a few notes.  - Notes?
不过不急着说 现在你可以把我送进监狱了
But they can wait. You can take me to jail now.
哦 不 不 不 我在想要不要再狠点 你死定了！
Oh, no, no, no. I was thinking more like the morgue. You're dead!
哇 哇 哇 游戏可不是这样玩的
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. This isn't how you play the game.
游戏结束
Game over.
[如果出现紧急情况 按此按钮]
中央机器人！
Brain-bots!
我要休战！
I'm calling time out!
休战？休战！休战！
Time out? Time out! Time out!
中央机器人 开启故障安全模式
Brain-bots, initiate the fail-safe.
猜猜怎么了 巴斯特・布朗先生？这可是铜做的
Guess what, Buster Brown? It's made from copper.
对它 你可是束手无策啊
You're powerless against it.
我就是用它来打败… 大都会侠？
It's the very same metal used to defeat... Metro Man?
不要拿我和大都会侠比！
You should stop comparing me to Metro Man!
你躲得了一时 超级大坏蛋 你躲不了一世！
You can run, Megamind, but you can't hide!
我们得救了！我们得救了！
We're saved! We're saved!
你叫什么名字  新一代的英雄？
What's your name, new hero?
- 我叫太阳神  - 谢谢你！
- It's Titan.  - Thank you!
谢谢你！太阳神让我们重获自由了！
Thank you! Titan has freed us!
哦 那可不是什么“自由” 而是在新的统治之下
Oh, I wouldn't say "free." More like under new management.
- 你想干什么？ - 太阳神变得邪恶了
- What do you want?  - Titan's turned evil.
祝贺你 你的杰作再次让你事与愿违
Congratulations. Another one of your genius plans has backfired on you.
为什么我的管家 会让你上来呢？
And why did my doorman let you up?
卡洛斯啊
Carlos.
求你了 罗珊 别 别这样 我需要你的帮助
Please, Roxanne, no. No. I need your help.
你怎么会需要我的帮助？
Why do you need my help?
因为你是我所知道的 最聪明的人
Because you're the smartest person I know.
但你不能藏在这里啊
But you can't hide here.
铜球应该有效啊 为什么会没用呢？
The copper should have worked. Why didn't the copper work?
上次铜就很成功啊
The copper worked perfectly well last time.
铜球？你在说什么啊
Copper? You're not making any sense.
听着 如果我们找不到太阳神的弱点
Look, if we don't find Titan's weakness,
他会毁了整座城市
he'll destroy the whole city.
- 好吧 要我怎么帮你？ - 我们需要找到答案
- OK, how can I help?  - We need to find answers.
你最了解大都会侠 他有什么可以藏身的地方吗？洞穴？
You knew Metro Man best. Did he have a hideout? A cave?
僻静的堡垒什么的？只要能给我们提供线索就行
A solitary fortress of some kind? Anything that would give us clues.
好吧… 我倒是知道一个地方
Well... there is one place I know.
是你赋予了他超能力 你就不能解除吗？
You gave him these powers. Can't you just take them away?
我不能 我忘记隐形车停哪儿了 扩压器枪也就丢了
I can't. I lost my diffuser gun when I misplaced the invisible car.
那晚你丢下我 独自一人 在雨中行走
The night you dumped me. Alone. In the rain.
你有回头看吗？
Did you ever look back?
- 没有！ - 我巨大的蓝脑袋啊！
- No!  - My giant blue head!
我们到了
I guess we're here.
他就藏在这里啊
So, this is where he hid it.
时光飞逝啊 这是我以前的学校
After all these years. My old shcoolhouse.
对于那天晚上 我想跟你道歉
You know, I think there's an apology in order for the other night.
好吧 这还差不多 但快点说
OK, that would be nice, but make it quick.
我们还有很多棘手的问题要解决
We have much more pressing matters to deal with.
哇噢 真不敢相信 他一直都留着这些东西
Wow. I can't believe he kept all this stuff.
我还记得他穿着这衣服的样子
I remember when he wore that.
- 我们不该在这儿专心点吗？ - 没错 当然 好的 专心
- Shouldn't we try to stay focused here?  - Yes, of course. Right. Focused.
嘿 快过来看啊
Hey. Come over and look at this.
怎么了？你发现什么了？
What is it? What did you find?
看啊
Look.
杯子里有冰块
This glass has ice cubes in it.
没错 这在天气变冷的情况下 很常见
Yes, that's what happens when water gets cold.
不是 我想说的是 冰到现在都没有融化
No, what I'm saying is, don't you think it's a little odd
你不觉得奇怪吗？
that the ice hasn't melted yet?
这就是生命伟大的奥秘之一
One of life's great mysteries.
嘿
Hey.
我们目前收到确切消息
We now have confirmed reports.
太阳神 本以为是这座城市新一代的英雄 现已变得邪恶
Titan, first thought to be this city's new hero, has turned evil.
这座城市从未被如此摧残过
The city has never seen this level of destruction.
要是大都会侠还活着该有多好
If only Metro Man were still alive.
- 你还活着？ - 你竟然没死
- You're alive?  - You're alive.
- 我没死  - 但我 我们…
- I'm alive.  - But I, we...
我们看到了你的尸体啊！你是死了啊！
We saw your skeleton! You were dead!
你是鬼吗？
Are you a ghost?
你最好能有个好理由 解释一下这件事
There had better be an amazing explanation for this.
说话啊  幽灵
Speak, apparition.
好 好 好
OK. OK, OK, OK.
你们应该知道真相
You both deserve the truth.
一切还要从天文台说起
It all started back at the observatory.
罗珊被绑架了 我准备去阻止你
Roxanne was kidnapped. I was gonna stop you.
我那天状态不好
My head wasn't in the game that day.
我们就像走过场一样
We were kind of going through the motions.
因此… 利用我的超级速度
So... using my super-speed,
我决定先清醒清醒
I decided to go clear my head.
开火！
Fire!
我突然意识到
Then I realized,
我们这辈子一直在玩不变的愚蠢的扮演游戏
we had done this same silly charade our entire lives.
我想抛掉这种感觉
I tried to get my mind off how I was feeling,
但我还是感到压抑
but I just felt stuck.
我开始意识到 除了超能力
I began to realize, despite all my powers,
大都会市的每个人都有我所没有的东西: 选择
each and every citizen of Metro had something I didn't: A choice.
从我记事以来 总是城市需要我干什么 我就干什么
Ever since I can remember, I've always had to be what the city wanted me to be.
有没有想过我想做什么呢？
But what about what I wanted to do?
然后 我突然想到
Then it suddenly hit me.
我是有的选的
I do have a choice.
我想怎样就怎样
I can be whatever I want to be.
没人要求你一生都要是个英雄
No one said this hero thing had to be a lifetime gig.
但你也不能说不干就不干
You can't just quit, either.
就是在那个时候 我想到了一个绝妙的注意… 伪造我的死亡
That's when I got the brilliant idea... to fake my death.
铜夺走了我的能量
Copper drains my powers.
你害怕铜？
Your weakness is copper?
你的死亡光线射出的那瞬间 我从未感觉如此轻松过
Once your death ray hit, I'd never felt so alive.
因此我从附近的医学院借了一具骷髅
So I borrowed a prop from a nearby nursing school.
大都会侠终于死了
Metro Man was finally dead.
音乐男诞生了！
And Music Man was born!
- 音乐男？ - 那样我可以继续用这个图标
- Music Man?  - That way I could keep my logo.
- 为什么？ - 你再说一遍？
- 'Cause of wha?  - Come again?
我终于可以自由地发挥我的能量…
I was finally free to get in touch with my true power...
比如编写一首抒情的歌啦
weaving lyrical magic.
来听听这个怎么样
Check this out.
# 我有一双慧眼 #
# I have eyes that can see #
# 可以看清整个世界… #
# Right through lead... #
- 你太差劲了！ - 很显然 你很有音乐方面的天赋
- You're horrible!  - Granted, you have talent.
但现在外面有一个疯子要摧毁我们的… 你的城市
But there's a mad man out there destroying our... your city.
你怎么能这样？！
How could you do this?!
市民都那么信任你 而你却抛弃了他们
The people of this city relied on you, and you deserted them!
你把我们落在了他手上！
You left us in the hands of him!
- 你别见怪  - 不会 我跟你想的一样
- No offense.  - No, I'm with you.
听着 我们需要你
Look, we need your help.
对不起 真的对不起
I'm sorry. I really am.
我不会出去的
I'm done.
你知道吗 小兄弟 世间有阴就有阳
You know, little buddy, there's a yin for every yang.
哪里有邪恶 哪里就会有正义与之对抗
If there's bad, good will rise up against it.
我用了很长的时间才找到自己的使命
It's taken me a long time to find my calling.
现在你也该寻找自己的使命了
Now it's about time you find yours.
嘿 谁需要他帮忙？
Hey, who needs him?
我们自己就可以打败太阳神
We can beat Titan ourselves.
我们可以会坏蛋老巢 带一些激光枪
I say we go back to the evil lair, grab some ray guns,
偷偷躲起来 然后一举消灭他
hold him sideways, and just go all gangsta on him.
我们做不到的
We can't.
难道就这样了吗？你就这么放弃了？
So that's it? You're just giving up?
我是坏人 我不能拯救世界 我不能上天堂
I'm the bad guy. I don't save the day, I don't fly off into the sunset,
我也不能跟喜欢的女孩在一起
and I don't get the girl.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
除非有人出手营救我们 不然一切将被摧毁
Unless someone comes to our aid soon, all may be lost.
成千上万的人们已经离开了这座城市
Thousands have already fled the city in a mass exodus.
剩下的市民如果没有接到进一步通知 只能呆在室内
Remaining citizens are warned to stay indoors until further notice.
政府部分已经发出警告
Authorities have issued a warning
要人们千万不要靠近市中心区域
to stay out of the downtown area at all costs.
哈尔啊！
Hal!
让我猜猜 看到我这么厉害
Let me guess. After seeing how awesome I am,
你终于想要跟我在一起了？但我已经不在乎你了
you've finally come to your senses? Well, I'm over you.
- 我是来阻止你的 哈尔  - 就凭你？哦 哇塞
- I've come to stop you, Hal.  - You? Oh, wow.
好啊 你打算怎么做 把我报道死吗？
OK, what are you gonna do, report me to death?
我想要跟你讲道理
I was going to try reasoning with you.
你和我 我们一起工作了很长时间 我了解你
You and I, we worked together for a long time. I know you.
你根本就不了解我 你从来就没有花过时间来了解我
You don't know me. You never took the time to know me.
这是我们第一次在外面晃悠
This is the first time we've hung out socially,
我就要摧毁这座城市了！
and it's when I'm about to destroy the city!
我要跟那个真实的哈尔说话
I want to talk to the real Hal.
那个曾经喜欢做一个摄影记者
I want to talk to the guy who loved being a cameraman,
喜欢吃调味酱 喜欢看书的哈尔
and eating dip, and being a nerd,
而不是像你现在这样疯狂的哈尔
and being not as scary as the Tighten Hal.
太晚了！
Too late!
打乱了我们的安排…
interrupting our scheduled...
发生离奇事件…
extraordinary events taking place...
山谷的大量热量和…
Heat in the valley and...
超级大坏蛋！
Megamind!
你跟我的恩怨还没有了结呢
You and I have some unfinished business.
我会在都会巨塔等你
I'll be waiting at Metro Tower.
哦 为了让你不放我鸽子…
Oh, and just so you don't get cold feet...
是罗珊
Roxanne.
来吧 洛茜 呼唤你的英雄来救你
Come on, Roxie, call for your hero to come rescue you.
超级大坏蛋 我不知道你有没有在听 但如果你在听
Megamind, I don't even know if you're listening, but if you are,
你不可以放弃
you can't give up.
我认识的那个超级大坏蛋从来不会轻易言败的
The Megamind I knew would never have run from a fight,
就算他知道他的胜算为零
even when he knew he had absolutely no chance of winning.
那就是你最大的优点
It was your best quality.
现在 你需要做回你自己
You need to be that guy right now.
这个城市需要你
The city needs you.
我需要你
I need you.
罗珊啊
Roxanne.
你有一个小时
You have one hour.
不要让我久等
Don't keep me waiting.
监狱长！监狱长！听我说！你必须放我出去！
Warden! Warden! Listen to me! You have to let me go!
必须有人要去阻止这一切！
Tighten has to be stopped!
抱歉 超级大坏蛋 你还有八十八个终身监禁在身
Sorry, Megamind. You still have 88 life sentences to go.
你有足够的时间反省你所做的一切
Plenty of time to reflect on what you've done.
你要我说出来吗？我来说
Did you want to hear me say it? I'll say it.
好吧 发自我最肮脏的肺腑
Here it is, from the blackest part of my heart.
对不起！
I am sorry!
我不相信
Not buying it.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我曾让这个城市无数次陷入恐慌
I've terrorized this city countless times.
创造出一个英雄 结果却发现是一个恶棍
Created a hero who's turned out to be a villain.
我对罗珊撒了谎 还有…
I lied to Roxanne, and...
我最好的朋友 仆人 我将其视为草芥
my best friend Minion, I treated like dirt.
请不要让这座城市…
Please don't make this city...
还有罗珊为我的错误行为买单
don't make Roxanne pay for my wrongdoings.
我接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
仆人 你这条出色的小鱼 是你
Oh, Minion, you fantastic fish, you.
我们还等什么呢？出发吧
What are we waiting for? We'd better get going.
你骗到我了
You got me.
- 祝你们好运 伙计们！ - 我们去送死啦！
- Good luck, fellas!  - We're gonna die!
等等 你说什么？
Wait, what?
嘿 大都会的窝囊废们 这里是都会巨塔
Hey, Metro losers. This is Metro Tower.
有人说这应该是我们城市实力的象征
They say it's supposed to be a symbol of our city's strength.
但对我来说 它让我想起那天
But for me, it's a reminder of the day
这个女人深深地伤透了我的心 所以我恨死它了！
this woman ferociously ripped out my heart. And I hate reminders!
救命！
Help!
求你不要这样 我知道你还有善良的一面的 哈尔
Please don't do this. I know there's still good in you, Hal.
你太天真了 洛茜
You're so naive, Roxie.
即使人们一点都不善良 你也总能看到他们善良的一面
You see the good in everybody, even when it's not there.
你真会幻想
You're living a fantasy.
世界上根本就没有复活之神 没有牙仙
There is no Easter Bunny, there is no Tooth Fairy,
也没有英国女王
and there is no Queen of England.
这才是现实 你醒醒吧！
This is the real world, and you need to wake up!
你居然敢挑战超级大坏蛋？
You dare challenge Megamind?
一山难容二虎！
This town isn't big enough for two super-villains!
哦 你是个老虎 没错！但只是个纸老虎！
Oh, you're a villain all right! Just not a super one!
是吗？有区别吗？
Yeah? What's the difference?
你好好看看吧！
Presentation!
- 我知道你一定会回来的  - 好吧 我也是被逼无奈
- I knew you'd come back.  - Well, that made one of us.
- 你有什么计划？ - 呃 计划就是不能死掉
- What's the plan?  - Well, it mostly involves not dying.
我喜欢这个计划
I like that plan.
塔！
Building!
快一点！让这玩意儿跑快点！
Go faster! Make this thing go faster!
我失去控制了！
I can't control it!
不
No.
嗯 真是易如反掌
Well, that was easy.
看来现在就剩一个没解决了
Looks like there's only one loose end now.
请爱护我们的公共交通工具
Please, let's have a little respect for public transportation.
你回来了！
You came back!
你说的对 罗珊 我本来就不应该走的
You were right, Roxanne. I never should have left.
你… 你不是死了吗
I... I thought you were dead.
我… 我怎么可能死呢
My death was... greatly exaggerated.
看来 你就是大家说的那个混蛋了
So, you're the punk I've heard about.
对不起 我已经尽力了
I'm sorry. I did the best I could.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
仆人？
Minion?
哒哒 吓一跳吧！
Surprise!
他才是真正的英雄
He's the real hero.
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
除了监狱
Going somewhere?
你还想去哪儿啊？
Besides jail?
别 别打脸 哥们 求你了
No, not in the face, man. Please.
如果你知道为自己着想 太阳神 就滚出大都会市！
If you know what's good for you, Titan, you'll stay out of Metrocity!
- 我会滚的！ - 永远别回来！
- You got it!  - For good!
演得不错 小姐
Pretty sneaky, sis.
不过我认识的人中 只有一个把这里称作“大都会市”
But there's only one person I know who calls this town "Metrocity."
就是你
You.
你一定觉得很好玩吧？
Bet you think it's really funny?
你们都来嘲笑这个真正的大英雄吧？
Let's all laugh at the really cool guy?
呵 不过也笑不了多久了
Well, you're not gonna be laughing for long.
隐形汽车
The invisible car.
嘿！还记得我把你甩了的那个晚上吗？
Hey! Remember that night that I dumped you?
你现在跟我谈这个？
You're bringing this up now?
好吧 当时我确实回头了！
Well, I did look back!
你回头了？真的？
You did? You did?
是的 你现在也要回头看一下！
Yes! And you should look back right now!
哦 我懂了！
Oh, I get it!
这是你最后一次耍我了！
This is the last time you make a fool out of me!
是我让你变成大英雄的
I made you a hero.
只是你自作孽不可活
You did the fool thing all by yourself.
你真可怜
You're so pathetic.
不管你站在哪一边 你总是失败者
No matter what side you're on, you're always the loser.
失败也是有好处的
There's a benefit to losing.
失败乃成功之母
You get to learn from your mistakes.
哦 开什么玩笑！
Oh, you've got to be kidding me!
仆人 如果我能活下来 要让你吃不了兜着走
Minion, if I live, I will kill you.
好好飞一下吧！
Enjoy your flight!
超级大坏蛋！
Megamind!
这就是事情的经过了
So this is how it ends.
要是平时我一定会记上 这是我最后一次光荣的失败
Normally, I'd chalk this up to my last glorious failure.
但是今天不行
But not today.
怎么说呢？固习难除吧
What can I say? Old habits die hard.
永别了 洛茜
Say bye-bye, Roxie.
哈罗
Ollo.
坏家伙的下场 就是失败！
The thing about bad guys, they always lose!
- 你成功了 你赢了  - 嗯…
- You did it. You won.  - Well...
我终于有理由去赢了 就是你
I finally had a reason to win. You.
仆人！
Minion!
我看不到了 这又冷… 又热 漆黑一片 头晕脑胀的
Can't see. It's cold and... warm, and dark and light.
是我 仆人 我就在这儿
It's me, Minion. I'm right here.
你和我 我们一起经历了很多的冒险
We've had a lot of adventures together, you and I.
是的 仆人
We have, Minion.
虽然说… 大多时候都输的很惨
I mean... most of them ended in horrible failure,
但今天我们赢了 是吧 老大？
but we won today. Didn't we, sir?
是的 仆人 多亏了你 我们成功了
Yes, Minion, we did it. Thanks to you.
指令: 咱们现在是好人了
Code: We're the good guys now.
收到指令: 我猜是的
Code: I guess we are.
哦 哦 哦 我要死了！也许 就这样了！
Oh, oh, oh, I'm going! I think this, this is it!
我要… 要死了…
I'm going... going far...
真是堪称影后啊
What a drama queen.
嗯 感觉好多了 可能只要游个泳就好了
You know, I'm feeling much better now. I guess I just needed a swim.
他吓到你了吧？
He had you, didn't he?
可爱的仆人 不要那样看着我
Classic Minion. Don't give me that face.
他那张小脸蛋会让你神魂颠倒的
He reels you in with that little face.
- 看他的表情  - 我们成功啦！
- Look at that face.  - We did it!
我们赢啦！
We did it!
- 第一场胜利拿下！ - 你成功了！
- Fist pump!  - You did it!
我们赢咯 赢咯 赢咯！
We won, we won, we won!
别过来 你们这些野蛮人！
Get back, you savages!
抱歉！抱歉 他只是还没有习惯接受赞扬
Sorry! Sorry. He's just not used to positive feedback.
真有趣 也许命运并不是上天注定的…
Funny, I guess destiny is not the path given to us...
而是掌握在我们自己手里
but the path we choose for ourselves.
好了 把你的手举起来
All right, put your hands in the air.
现在把你们的钱包都拿过来
Now hand over your wallets.
开玩笑的！
I'm just kidding!
玩笑而已！
Just kidding!
我必须承认 好人有好报
I have to admit, being good has its perks.
你知道吗 你穿白色衣服还真不错
You know, you look pretty good in white.
超级大坏蛋 你可不可以…
Megamind, if you plea...
喂 你挡着我的孩子了
Hey. My kid can't see.
不好意思 朋友
Sorry, my friend.
做的不错 小兄弟 我知道你可以的
Way to go, little buddy. I knew he had it in him.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
超级大坏蛋 大都会市的守护者！
Megamind, defender of Metro City!
知道吗 我喜欢这样的音乐
You know, I like the sound of that.
放音乐！
Hit it!
超级大坏蛋！超级大坏蛋！超级大坏蛋！超级大坏蛋！
Megamind! Megamind! Megamind! Megamind!
我是坏人！我是坏人！对 就是这样！
I'm bad! I'm bad! That's right. Yeah!
老大 你真的需要经常掏掏口袋了
Sir, you really need to empty your pockets more often.
这是我一生中最糟糕的一天了
This has been the worst day of my entire life.
不用担心
No worries.